大家好 我是 Saron Yitbarek
Hi everybody, I'm Saron Yitbarek
这里是红帽的原创播客节目《代码英雄》的特别番外篇
and this is a special bonus episode of Command Line Heroes,
an original podcast from Red Hat.
我们的节目在第 2 季去了很多地方
This podcast went a lot of places in Season 2.
我们探索了编程语言、数据大爆炸、
we explored programming languages, data overload,
安全危机 以及无服务器时代的到来
security crises, the advent of serverless.
我们甚至去了火星
I mean, we even went to Mars.
但是 在第 2 季结束之后 我们还有一个地方要去
But after closing out Season 2, there was still one more place we wanted to go.
我们要走进推广大使和思想领袖们的认识当中
We wanted to go inside the minds of the advocates and thought leaders
他们着手塑造了开发者工作的面貌
who help shape all the work that developers do.
有时 他们被称为"开发者推广大使"
Sometimes they're called developer advocates
或者说他们担任开发者关系的职位
or they're in developer relations
又有时 他们被称作开发者布道师
or they're developer evangelists.
从开发者的角度来看 无论他们的具体头衔是什么
Whatever their exact titles, from the developer's perspective,
他们似乎或多或少都在做相同的事情
they seem to do a lot of the same things.
你在会议上见过他们发表主题演讲
You've seen them give keynotes at conferences.
你在播客上听过他们接受采访 就像在本期节目中一样
You've heard them getting interviewed on podcasts, like this one.
你可能还阅读过他们的博文
You've probably read their blog posts.
但他们是谁呢？
But who are they,
他们发声 又能做到什么？
and what exactly are they using their voices to get done?
为了迎接 2019 年 我们为大家召集了一次优秀人物的圆桌会议
To ring in 2019, we've pulled together a roundtable of amazing people for you.
尽管他们的头衔各不相同 但他们的目的是一致的
While their titles are all different, their purpose is the same.
他们的工作是帮助开发人员 并确保其声音和需求能被听到
They're here to help developers and make sure their needs and voices are heard.
这些人都是典型的代码英雄
These folks are classic command line heroes.
出身于湾区
From the Bay Area,
Sandra Persing 是 Mozilla 的“全球策略师”
Sandra Persing is a Mozilla Global Strategist
也是 DevRel 峰会的创始人
and creator of the DevRel Summit.
嗨 Saron
Hi, Saron.
你好
Hello.
还有同样来自旧金山的 Ricky Robinett
And also in San Francisco we have Ricky Robinett.
他是 Twilio 的“开发者网络总监”
He's the Director of the Developer Network over at Twilio.
怎么说？
What's up?
从凤凰城外和我一起来的是 Robyn Bergeron
Joining me from just outside of Phoenix is Robyn Bergeron,
红帽的社区架构师
a community architect at Red Hat.
嗨！你好吗？
Hi there. How are you?
我很好
I'm doing great.
看到你真高兴
Excellent.
在不同的地方 这份工作的践行者被冠以不同的头衔
So there are a lot of titles floating around.
例如“开发者推广大使” “开发者布道师”、“开发者关系”
There's Developer Advocate, Developer Evangelist, Developer Relations,
对于新事物来说 基本定义非常重要
and with all these new things, basic definitions are super important.
因此 我认为 好的起点是
So, I think a good place to start is
先定义这些头衔
just to define what these things are
尤其是定义你可以在这个领域做什么
and specifically, what you all do in this space.
所以 你能告诉我你的头衔是什么 以及这个头衔的意思吗
So, can you tell me your job title and what that title actually means?
Ricky 你先来
Ricky, let's start with you.
好 听着不错
Okay, sounds good.
我的头衔是“开发者网络总监”
My title is the Director of the Developer Network.
我有幸供职于一个开发者关系专家团队
What I have the privilege of doing is
serving a team of developer relations professionals.
我们有一个布道师团队
We have an evangelism team,
还有一个教育团队和一个社区团队
we have a education team and we have a community team.
因此 这绝对是一个大杂烩
So, it's definitely a mishmash of all the different titles of you hear,
有你听说过的各种不同的头衔
我们将其汇集在这个团队之中
we kind of collect them on the team.
厉害啊 Sandra 你呢？
Awesome. And Sandra, what about you?
我在 Mozilla 担任“全球策略师” 负责管理活动和赞助
I am at Mozilla as the Global Strategist for events and sponsorship
我与 Mozilla 新兴技术小组的开发者拓展团队合作
and I work with our developer outreach team
in the emerging tech group at Mozilla.
我通常会将我的日常活动解释为
I usually explain my day to day activities as
大量的研究、交流和探索
a lot of research and communications and explorations
在此之后 就是评估和做出决定
that really leads to evaluating and deciding,
决定我们该怎样使用资源：
you know, how we should all invest our resources:
这包括时间 金钱 纪念品 扩音器之类的
our time, money, swag, speakers, et cetera,
来回馈开发者社区
in order to give back to the developer community,
同时也从开发者社区得到反馈
but also to receive feedback from the developer communities.
这份工作既有布道的一面 也有推广的一面
So both the evangelism side and the advocate side.
很棒 Robyn 该你了
Awesome. And Robyn, you're up next.
你好 好吧 我的正式头衔是“社区架构师”
Hi. Well so, my official title is Community Architect.
人们就我这个头衔有过很多问题
I get a lot of questions about this title.
我曾被称为“社区经理”
I've gone by Community Manager.
也曾被称为“开发者推广大使”
I've gone by Developer Advocate.
我甚至还曾经做过“运维推广大使”
I've even gone by Operations Advocate at one job in the past.
但是我想 我做的是…嗯 你知道
But I like to think of what I do is, you know,
像是“社区经理”之类头衔
when you're a community manager,
这种头衔像是在说 你负责管理社区里的人
like the idea that you're really managing all these people
但他们其实都是自己好心来贡献的
who are contributing out of the goodness of their heart
这种说法 在某种意义上 有点蠢
is sort of a silly notion.
所以 我喜欢把我的工作当成是构建一个框架
So, I like to think of what I do as building frameworks
让人们可以顺利地参与其中
in which people can actually successfully participate
确保过程中没有障碍
and make sure that roadblocks aren't in their way
并确保他们可以完成所有他们想要做的事情
and that they can get done all the things they want to get done.
Ricky 因为你基本上是在负责整个开发者网络
And Ricky, since you are essentially the Director of the entire network,
你不只是推广团队、布道团队或者社区团队的一员
you're not just in advocacy or evangelism or community,
你更像是在负责运行整个项目
it kind of feels like you're running the whole show.
你是怎样理解“推广”的任务的
How do you understand this idea of being an advocate
是为了开发者而推广 还是向开发者推广？
either for developers or advocating to developers?
这是个好问题
Yeah, that's a great question.
Phil Nash 是我们团队中的一名布道师
Phil Nash, who's one of the evangelists on our team
他对此有很好的认识 我要剽窃他的点子
had a great framing for this that I'm going to steal,
我们可以从很多不同的角度来解释这份工作
which is we have a lot of different ways of describing what we do,
但说到底 我们的工作其实就是帮助他人
but ultimately a lot of them just being help.
好 这个我喜欢
I like that. Yeah.
我们帮助开发人员
We help developers,
有时候这些帮助看起来就像是在 Stack Overflow 上回答问题
and so sometimes that help looks like answering a question on Stack Overflow.
有时看起来像是打造新工具
Sometimes it looks like building a new tool.
有时看起来像组织活动
Sometimes it looks like organizing an event
有时又像是对开发中的产品进行内部改动
and then sometimes it looks like initiating a product change internally.
因此 我认为这就是我所听说过的最好的看法
so, I think that's the best framing I've heard
我们负责提供帮助
is really our responsibility is to help.
的确
Absolutely.
Sandra 你的职位让我感兴趣的一点是
Sandra, what I'm so interested in about your position
你不光是个策略师 还是个“全球”策略师
is that you're not just a Strategist, you're a Global Strategist
让世界各地的开发人员组织起来
and you're all over the world trying to bring developers together
并且帮助他们 这是你在 Mozilla 的工作的一部分
and help them as part of your job at Mozilla.
在全球范围内 “推广”、“倡导”会是什么样的呢？
When we think about advocacy on a global scale, what does that look like?
在不同的国家、不同的大洲之间 这份工作的含义会有所不同吗？
Does it mean something different across different countries, continents?
当然有不同
Yeah, absolutely.
我们今年刚刚在新加坡举办了第三届 DevRel 年度峰会
We just wrapped our third annual DevRel Summit this year in Singapore
在前两年 我们是在西雅图举办的这项活动
and the past two years, we hosted the event in Seattle
而到了新加坡
and getting out to Singapore,
我们看到了不同的视角
we saw a different perspective.
当我们走出湾区时
When we get outside of the Bay Area,
就连某些最基本的组织方式都需要做出改变
it can be something as basic as,
比如 在线下 如何保证一切运行如常
you know, how do we make sure everything just works offline,
连接性是个大问题
because connectivity is such an issue
再比如 我们该怎样才能
or something like how do we just make sure
使一名在印尼工作的开发者在峰会中与社区充分互动
a developer who's working in Indonesia feels just connected to a developer community,
无论他是线上参会 还是来到现场
whether that's online or onsite through meetups.
我们总会发现 所谓的“基础”
And always going back to recognizing that some of our quote unquote "basic things,"
一些我们看来稀松平常的事 比如在湾区简单开个会
some of our easy things like creating a simple meetup in the Bay Area,
这再常见不过了 对吧？
which is so a dime a dozen, right?
你高呼一声“我要参会” 就会发现到处都有聚会可以参加
You throw a rock and there's a meetup everywhere
这种情况在世界上其他地方并非常态
is still something really special
对于 比如说 越南的开发者来说
and something that a developer in let's say Vietnam
这种聚会可能对他们非常宝贵 非常重要
still sees to be incredibly important and valuable
能极大地丰富他们作为开发者的社区生活
and enriching their developer community life.
我发现 大家都以某种方式提到了社区
And one thing I'm noticing is that everyone has mentioned community in some way.
我自己也运营着一个社区
And I run a community myself.
它叫做 Code Newbie 然而我经常被一些公司招募
I do Code Newbie and I regularly get recruited by companies
作为他们的布道师或社区经理
to be an evangelist or a community manager for their company
有一件事 我一直都有点儿担心
and one thing that I've always been a little worried about,
一想到就会有点害怕
maybe a little squeamish about is thinking,
我在想 我花了三四年时间维持这个社区
okay, I've spent the last three, four years taking care of this community
不求回报地付出
with no strings attached,
从自己的角度看来 我已经尽我所能
on my terms,I'm doing what I think is best.
但如果我为一家公司工作
But if I work for a company,
我就必须要牺牲这些吗？
then will I have to sacrifice that?
我是否需要
Am I going to be in a position
将公司需求置于社区的需求之上？
where I have to put the company before the needs of the community
我该如何平衡这种关系呢？
and how do I balance that relationship?
所以我在想 Robyn
So I'm wondering, Robyn,
或许可以问问你这个“社区架构师”
maybe we could start with you as a Community Architect,
你是如何区分这两者的呢？
how do you separate that?
或者说 你是如何平衡这两者的？
How do you maintain that church and state relationship, so to speak?
这种平衡确实值得深思熟虑
Well, it's certainly an interesting balance.
我想说 我以前担任过 Fedora 项目负责人
I mean, one of my former jobs was actually being the Fedora project leader.
你知道 Fedora 是 RHEL 的上游
And you know, Fedora is the upstream for Red Hat Enterprise Linux,
所以在这个职位上 寻找平衡就是工作的一部分
you know, part of your role there is really to be sort of the balancing act, right?
天平的一边是“社区的人们是否开心”
The balance between are people happy in the community,
另一边则是“公司是否对社区满意”
is the company happy with what the community is doing
要达到的效果是 每个人都是快乐大家庭的一员
and making sure that basically everybody's one big happy family.
你懂的 如果你在尽力做这种事
And you know, I think when you're doing your job best in that position
你基本上注定了要
yeah, you're pretty much bound to
时不时地激怒公司决策层的某些人
probably anger someone at the corporate headquarters once in a while.
但是你也知道 最终还是要用结果来证明 对吧？
But you know, the proof is in the pudding at the end of the day. Right?
人们总是问我 你是如何平衡
People ask me all the time like, how do you balance, you know,
Ansible 和红帽之间的关系的
what's going on with Ansible and Red Hat
你知道 当 Ansible 被红帽收购时
and you know, like when Ansible got bought by Red Hat,
大家的反应就像是 “老天 红帽会接管所有的决策吗”
like, oh my God, is Red Hat going to take it over
"他们是不是要干什么坏事 比如取消 Ubuntu 支持之类的？"
and do something terrible to it like get rid of, Ubuntu support?
这完全跟整个项目的目的是背道而驰的
And it was like, that would be defeating the whole purpose
of having this entire project.
我们能有 4000 名贡献者 肯定不是因为我们的项目很糟糕
Like, we haven't gotten to 4,000 contributors by being terrible.
确保你的管理层信任你
Making sure that your management trusts in you
和员工之间要一直保持消息畅通
and that you have clear communication with folks all the time
知道当下发生了什么
about what's actually going on
避免意想不到的情况
and that there aren't surprises on either side of the aisle
这直接影响到你是会成功
is part of what makes the difference between success
还是 因为预想不足 而没办法保证成功
and maybe not always success, but certainly people being surprised.
嗯嗯 确实
Mm-hmm. Absolutely.
Ricky 你呢？
And Ricky, what about you?
你觉得该怎么处理“政教关系”
How do you think about church and state
如果你有那么多不同的职责的话？
in that relationship when you're doing so many different things?
我认为你必须相信公司和技术
I think you have to believe in the company and the technology.
你必须相信 你所带给开发人员的东西
You have to believe that what you are bringing to developers
将会对他们的生活、职业生涯和他们的公司产生影响
is going to have an impact on their lives and their careers and their companies.
在另一方面
And then on the flip side,
你得让高管们对你的工作方式和理念有信心
you have to have executives who believe in this approach to your work.
在这方面我们很幸运 我们的 CEO 自己就是开发者
So, we're very lucky that our CEO is a developer
在很多方面
and in many ways
他是我们和开发者社区打交道的原动力
was the driving force behind the way that we approach our developer community.
布道师的使命之一是激励开发者 并给他们以工具
Our evangelists have a mission to inspire and equip developers.
因此 有时我们会讨论
And so, there are times when we say,
像这样能起到激励的效果吗？能把装备推广给他们吗？
is this going to inspire and equip them?
起不到这种作用的事 我们就不去做
Because if it's not, we shouldn't really be doing it
因为这不是我们职责的一部分
because it's something that's outside of our purview.
Sandra 我觉得你有点儿优势
Sandra, I feel like you're a little bit at an advantage
因为 Mozilla 是非营利性的 对吧？所以我觉得 -
because Mozilla's a nonprofit, right? So I feel like maybe -
我刚想说呢
I was going to say.
跟我讲讲这个吧
Tell me about that.
我们 Mozilla 在历史上就是一家叛逆的公司
The history of Mozilla is that we're a rebellious company.
我们一直在反抗大企业 对吧
we've always rebelled against the corporate man, right?
我们源自于网景
The whole history of coming out of Netscape
我们的创始人之一是 Mitchell Baker
and with one of our founders, Mitchell Baker,
而我们的理想 是“确保互联网对每个人都是开放的免费资源”
in making sure that the web is and the Internet is an open and free resource for all.
我是说 直到现在 我们每个人
I mean, we still, every one of us,
Mozilla 的每个人都仍对这句格言深信不疑
every Mozillian believes this mantra and we hold it dear to our heart.
所以这家公司 很奇妙地 百分百地向社区侧倾斜
So it's absolutely an amazing company that has embraced the community side 100%.
Ricky 我还清楚地记得那件红色的运动夹克
So Ricky, I vividly remember the red, like, sports jacket
注：红色夹克是 Twilio 的一种内部奖励
发放给编写应用程序之后在全公司面前完成程序演示的员工
我还记得你亲自出马做的演示 你讲得棒极了
and I remember seeing you personally onstage doing these awesome demos
注：红色夹克是 Twilio 的一种内部奖励
发放给编写应用程序之后在全公司面前完成程序演示的员工
我感觉这种方式
it feels like that whole approach to
作为联系并帮助开发人员的方式 它非常新颖
connecting with developers and helping developers was very new.
你们 Twilio 的人是怎么想到这个主意的？
Where did that idea even come from at Twilio?
你这么说实在是过誉了
Well, that's very kind of you to say.
据我们所知 我们其实是站在巨人的肩膀上
We do really believe we stand on the shoulders of giants here.
比如说苹果的盖伊·川崎
You think of Guy Kawasaki with Apple,
在我们之前 早就有人用这种方式做营销了
of people doing this style of marketing way before us.
我们只是非常幸运
I think that we got to be fortunate enough
能在正确的时机把它带到开发者面前
to be at the right time to take this to developers.
很多人响应了召唤
And there's just so many people who came in
他们带来了解决问题的许多办法 以及不断进步的方式
with the idea of how we can do this and how to keep leveling up how we approached it.
不过我真不知道红色运动夹克是谁的主意
I don't actually know who invented the red track jacket though,
现在我得去探寻历史了
so now I need to go find the history
You gotta find that out.
你一定得找到答案
搞明白这是从哪里开始的
of where that started.
那是件很棒的夹克
That's a great jacket.
我知道 今天下午我的任务就是这个了
I know. That's my mission for this afternoon now.
我想知道 布道和推广的想法
And I'm wondering how has that idea of evangelism, and advocacy,
在 Twilio 是如何随着时间而发生变化的
how has that changed over time at Twilio,
考虑到你们
given the fact that, you know,
曾经只是一家创业公司 一家叛逆的初创公司
at one point you were a small little startup or a little rebellious startup,
现如今 你们成了一家大公司
and then now you're kind of a big company.
随着公司本身的变化 布道的形式又是如何变化的呢？
How is the shape of evangelism changed as the company itself has changed?
刚开始 我感觉我整一年 每一天都在参加黑客马拉松
Yeah, when I started here, I feel like I could have spent 365 days a year at hackathons
黑客马拉松（Hackathon）：又译为编程马拉松、黑客松 又称为黑客节（Hackfest）
是一种限时的活动 开发者与团队聚在一起 在限定的时间内完成开发 常见的时限从24小时到一周不等
在纽约 每周末你都得从五六个这种活动中选一个
and in New York every weekend you had to pick from five or six hackathons.
我们当初布道几乎都是在黑客马拉松活动上
So much of what we did with evangelism was the hackathon scene
而现在 场景不同了
and now, that's not the same scene.
最大的变化来自于公司外部而不是内部
Really, the biggest changes have been driven outside the company rather than inside.
我之前谈到布道师的任务 激励开发者 给他们以装备
So I talk about evangelists inspiring and equipping.
好的一方面在于 就算过了这些年 这点也没变
And so the nice thing is that hasn't changed in all the years,
达成任务的方式不断地在改变
so the ways that they inspire and equip keep going differently,
但使命本身并无任何变化
but the mission itself doesn't change.
那么 Robyn 随着 DevOps 和 DevSecOps 的兴起
And Robyn, with the rise of DevOps and DevSecOps,
你个人是怎么看待“推广”的？作为社区架构师 你又怎么看待？
what does advocacy look like for you and for being that community architect?
会有运维推广大使吗？
Is there gonna be a Ops advocate?
呃 运维推广大使其实是…
Well, actually that was ...
我辍学之后的第一份工作
I mean, my first job after dropping out of school,
我不推荐这样 孩子们 别在家干这个
don't recommend it, kids. Don't do that at home.
Stay in school.
留在学校里继续上学
听好了 我看着你呢 小姑娘
Listening. Look at looking at you, daughter.
我最开始其实是在摩托罗拉当系统管理员 当了有一些年头
My first job was actually as a SysAdmin at Motorola for a number of years
然后去当了 Fedora 的负责人 之后
and when I moved on from being in charge of Fedora,
跳槽去 Elastic Search 干了一段时间
I worked at Elastic Search for a while and you know,
那时候我的头衔是开发者推广大使
had this title of Developer Advocate and was like,
虽然我在大学里跟 C 语言搏斗了好几个学期
yeah, so I hacked my way through several semesters of C in college.
但是我的心一直都在运维这边
But my heart was always in operations.
我开始觉得 我真的是开发者推广大使吗？
I started feeling like am I really a developer advocate?
我感觉我怎么一直都在跟运维推广呢
I feel like I'm just advocating to ops folks mostly.
那之后我就开始自称“运维推广大使”
And I just started calling myself an operations advocate
没人对我这个叫法有过什么特别的反应
which nobody blinked an eye at.
所有人都只是说 “哦 这头衔还挺有意思”
Everyone said, well, that's a really cool title.
我其实 你懂的 我只是在做推广
I'm like, you know, I'm just advocating in general
大部分时候是向公司内部 告诉大家其他人都在做什么
mostly to the inside of my company about what everybody else is doing.
Sandra 我们之前聊到 “推广”和“布道”的任务
So Sandra, we talked about how advocacy and evangelism
在世界各地的不同面貌
looks different in different parts of the world,
我想知道 这些年以来
but I'm wondering over the years
随着我们变得越来越全球化 联系越来越紧密
as we become increasingly more global and more connected,
“布道”这份任务的整体形象 对你来说有改变过吗
has the larger picture, the larger shape of evangelism shifted over time for you?
你知道什么是"开发者关系"吗？
You know, what is developer relations?
我们展示产品的样子 像不像干推销的？
Are we pitching our product being more salesy?
你知道的 我也发现
You know, and I notice that
就算是大公司也不喜欢用这种推销式的策略了
even large corporations are moving away from that tactic.
要知道 保持真诚 用一片真心
Understanding that being authentic, being truly mindful
倾听开发者的需求 并给出回馈 这才是一切的关键
of listening and responding to the needs of developers is key above all else,
推销产品没办法让你成功
not pitching product.
我总会跟在 Mozilla 的团队分享一个理念
I always go back and share with my team at Mozilla
开发者是最聪明 最有创造力的客户群体
that developers are actually one of the smartest and creative customer base
至少我们要打交道的客户里是这样
that we'll ever work with.
他们大老远就能闻出来你说的话是不是放狗屁
They can smell that BS from miles away.
我们必须明智地选择放出信息的方式
So, we have to be smart about how we are sharing information,
要开动聪明才智 各尽所能
like it has to be a diverse group of talented and intelligent minds
一齐发挥创造力
all coming together to become creative
要像这样与开发者社区交流
in our approach of communicating to our developer community.
这个我喜欢
Oh, I really like that.
需要将许多不同的技能
I like this idea of many different skill sets,
还有背景 结合在一起 才能更好地服务开发者
I guess, backgrounds need to come together to really serve developers well
并帮助开发者自助
and to help developers help themselves, too.
当我回顾开发者推广大使的兴起时
When I think about the rise of developer advocates,
在我看来 它与开源的兴起息息相关
to me it feels very connected to the rise of open source.
感觉像是 开源贡献者越来越多
It almost feels like the more open source contributors there were
开源变得越来越重要
and the bigger deal open source became
大公司越来越看重它
and the more big companies took it seriously,
他们就不得不去
they almost had to
跟开源贡献者 跟开发者搞好关系
establish better relationships with these open source contributors, these developers,
这两者在我看来 关系很大
and it feels like those two are really connected to me.
我很好奇你们的看法
So I'm curious about your ideas about that.
Robyn 从你开始吧
So Robyn, let's start with you.
我的观察是正确的吗？
Is that true at all?
“推广大使”的这个想法与开源的兴起有所联系吗？
Is that idea of advocacy connected at all to the rise of open source?
如果你是一家卖软件的公司
If you are a company who is selling software
或者卖许可证 或者靠长期支持赚钱
that or selling whatever licenses, long termsupport,
无论一家开源公司采用怎么样的业务模式
you know, whatever your open source company's business model actually is,
如果你们无法得到反馈 并以此调整自身
if you don't have that feedback loop
或者你没有真正关注人们在说什么
or you're not actually paying attention to what people are saying,
你就会做出一看就有问题的东西
you're going to wind up delivering the proverbial wrong thing.
眼观六面耳听八方
And really being able to encompass that, you know, around the world
和自我孤立闭门造车
and just day to day in what you do
就是成功 和“做出有问题的作品” 之间的区别
is the difference between success and I guess making the wrong thing,
不会有人想浪费时间在后者上面
which nobody wants to spend time doing.
这是个坏主意
That's a bad idea.
这种一般都是坏主意
Yeah, that's generally a bad idea.
我想知道你们每个人
So, I want to know from each of you
各自都在关注什么 都在思考什么
what you all have been focusing on, really thinking about.
Ricky 先从你开始
So Ricky, let's start with you.
你想通过在Twilio的角色
What kind of improvements do you try to bring about
为开发者文化带来什么进步？
in the developer culture in your role at Twilio?
如果要让我说在跟开发者聊天的时候 最经常听到的一句话
If I were to say the phrase I've heard the most when I talk to developers,
那会是“我不是开发者 但是…”
it's, "I'm not a developer, but,"
我心里总是挂着的 最重要的事之一 恐怕就是这件了
and that's probably one of the biggest things that's always on my mind
把开发者的定义拓宽
is broadening the definition of developer.
对我们来说 冒牌者症候群极为常见
Imposter syndrome for so many of us is a very real thing.
奇妙的是 就算是你认识的某些最优秀的开发者 也会有这种毛病
It's just amazing how even some of the best developers you know are struggling with it.
对我来说 这就是我们能对文化做的最重要的改变之一
And for me, that's one of the biggest things we can all do in our culture
那就是允许一个人说 “你知道吗？我是个开发者”
is give people permission to say, "You know what? I am a developer.
“我写代码解决问题”
I am solving problems with code."
我最爱的故事之一 是
And so, one of my favorite stories is
在我们社区里 有个魔术师 他叫 Doug McKenziethat
we have a member of our community named Doug McKenziethat's a magician.
他自学了 PHP 好在魔术表演中使用科技
And he taught himself PHP so he could use tech in his magic tricks.
喔 那不错
Oh, neat.
Doug 是个很酷的人 因为他超级谦虚 他总是说
Doug is so cool because he was super humble about like,
“我不是开发者”
"Oh, I'm not a developer."
但你哪天就会发现
And suddenly you see, like,
他写的代码非常复杂 很多人可能一辈子都没见过这样的代码
he's writing more complicated code than many people have ever seen,
这些代码能做到令人震惊的事情
to do things that blow minds.
因此 我感觉世界上有许多 Doug McKenzies 这样的人
And so, I just feel like there's so many Doug McKenzies in the world
他们都在用代码做着伟大的事情
who are doing great things with code
我们有机会让他们成为社区的一份子
and we have the opportunity to give them permission to be part of the community
并获得与这些成就相匹配的身份
and to have an identity in that work.
我喜欢这个故事
I love that story
它让我想起我曾经为 Code Newbie 播客采访过的一个人
because it reminds me of someone I interviewed for the Code Newbie podcast actually,
她是一名作家 有很多写作任务
and she was a writer and she had a bunch of assignments
必须学习 Git 才能撰写有关 Git 的文章
where she had to learn Git in order to write about Git
她写了很多这方面的文章 又逐渐转向了其他的编程主题
and she'd written so many of these articles and it grew to be on other coding topics
最终 几年过去之后
and eventually, you know, a couple of years had passed
她成了一名开发者而不自知
and she'd essentially become a developer and didn't know it.
在我采访她的时候 我说
And by the time I interviewed her and I said,
“嗨 你知道自己是个开发者吗”
"Hey, do you know that you're a developer?"
她说：“不 我是个作家 ”
She's like, "No, I'm a writer."
我说 “你也可以两个都是 这两者并不互斥”
And I said, "You can be both. They're not mutually exclusive."
但话说回来 让人换个角度说
But yeah, that shift in perspective of saying,
“我写代码 我造软件 所以我能自称是个写代码的”
"Hey, I'm actually coding and creating, therefore I can now call myself a coder,"
这可不容易 要让人脑筋转过这个弯 可得费些时间
it's tough for people. It takes a while to get there.
是啊 的确
Yeah, absolutely.
对
Yeah.
Robyn 对你而言
So Robyn, for you,
你这几年中 带来的最积极的变化是什么？
what's been the most positive change that you've managed to push forward in recent years?
那就是 保证我们在扩张规模时不会失去方向
Just making sure that as we grow, that we're not losing track of the big picture,
我们的目标主要有几个 首先是让产品易于使用
that our main goals around keeping it simple for people to use,
其次是让项目易于贡献
simple for people to contribute to,
让它能解决实际生活中的问题
simple to actually get stuff done within your life,
很大一部分的工作 都是保证我们不偏离这些目标
making sure we're not losing track of that
还有一部分工作是争取工程上的帮助
or getting more engineering help
请人来帮忙管理项目结构
to just work on some of the structure of the actual project
保证一切都井井有条
and make sure that we're doing a good job of keeping all that stuff in order
我不清楚啊 我觉得这些都很重要
was, I don't know, I thought that was important.
我应该没办法因为这个拿诺贝尔和平奖
I don't know that I'm going to win a Nobel Peace Prize for that,
但我知道这些对许多贡献者都非常重要
but I know it's something that mattered a lot to lots of the contributors.
说得通
That works for me.
Sandra 你呢
Sandra, what about you?
这些年中 你作为全球策略师 带来的最积极的变化是什么？
What's been the most positive change that you've managed to push forward
in recent years as a Global Strategist?
我能立即想到两件事
Two things that really stand out from my mind is
其一是 拓展“开发者”这个词的定义 让开发者的人物形象多样化
expanding this definition, the persona of developer,
这件事非常重要
has been something that's been very important.
我们想扩张社区 对吧？
We'd love to grow our community, right?
那为什么要把开发者的定义和形象限制死呢？
So why restrict the definition and description of a developer?
我们在 Sundance 举办过一次座谈会 来的都是些名人
When we did a panel at Sundance with some famous names
Reggie Watts 和 Chris Milk 之类
like Reggie Watts and Chris Milk,
我们给了电影制作者、制片人、决策者一个机会
we gave an opportunity for filmmakers, producers, decision makers to say,
让他们能说“这个我们也能做
to say, "Oh, we can do that, too.
我们不必被‘电影制作者’的身份框住”
We don't have to be bound by restrictions
of what can we do as creative filmmakers."
“我们能使用技术 成为开发者
We can adopt technology, and we too can become developers,
这是非常耳目一新的体验”
and that was very refreshing to see.
另一次 我们在 Mozilla 和一位艺术家合作
Another moment that we had at Mozilla was bringing an artist,
他叫 Ian Brill 来自芝加哥 是灯光师
Ian Brill, a light artist in Chicago,
我们一起做的项目叫做“拱门”
to work with us on a project that we label Arch,
我们用塑料做了个巨大的、带 LED 灯、能发光的结构
and we brought this huge plastic light, LED light,
用 7 个树莓派编程控制
with seven Raspberry Pis being programmed structure,
然后把它带到两个重要的 JavaScript 开发者活动上
to two significant JavaScript developer events this year.
为了吸引更多的编程者
And in order to invite more programmers,
就算他们不自称开发者也行
whether they call themselves developers or not,
让他们尝试 Mozilla 今年大力倡导的两种编程语言
to try out two languages that Mozilla was advocating this year pretty strongly,
WebAssembly 和 Rust
WebAssembly and Rust.
我们简单制作了两种模板 鼓励他们“来试试看”
So we created two simple templates, to say, "Try it out,"
但我们想推动的不是编程本身
but it's not programming that we wanted to push towards.
不是“写代码”这件事
It's not coding.
而是“这里有几行代码
It was, "Yes, there's some lines of code.
这是编程语言 但你会想要
It's language, but what you want to do is
能把自己写出的代码 转化为艺术”
create a few lines that now can translate into art,"
这让许多新人进到了我们的群体之中
and that brought so many new people into our fold,
他们真的到了我们的桌子前面
literally brought them to our table,
等到他们写了代码
and then they would write their lines of code,
去拱门下走一趟
go and walk over under the Arch,
就能看到他们写的灯光表演在整个结构上循环播放
to see their light expressions now being looped in the structure.
真妙啊
That was amazing.
这真棒 这实在是太美了
Wow. That sounds beautiful, absolutely beautiful.
所以 我想 我们有提到“为开发者做推广”
So, I'm wondering, when we talk about advocating for developers,
也谈到了一大堆社区的事
and we talked a ton about community,
说到底 “推广”和“布道”的重点在于
and this idea of at the end of the day,
无论我们的职位头衔是什么 我们的使命都是帮助他人
whatever our job titles are, we're really just trying to help people,
我想知道 开发者需要怎样的帮助？
what do developers need help with?
Ricky 从你开始
Ricky, let's start with you.
开发者们都向你求助过什么？
What do developers say that they need from you?
喔 这是个好问题
Wow. Yeah, that is a good question.
我们发现 有这么一回事
I think that one of the things that we've found is that,
科技变化得实在太快
like technology's changing so quickly,
我们很多时候被问到的问题就是
and a lot of what we get asked about is just,
“我从哪里开始？我首先要做什么？我怎么知道我走的路是正确的呢？”
"Where do I start? What do I do first? How do I know I'm on the right path?"
这可能是我们投入最多的领域之一
For us, that's probably one of the areas we have been investing the most,
我们一般管这个叫做 帮助人们发现
is we call it like helping people discover
他们用代码改变世界的能力
their power to change the world with code.
很美妙 我赞成
Oh, that's beautiful. I approve.
谢谢 对 这很棒
Well, thank you. Yes. That's exciting.
为了这个 我们做了一款叫做 Twilio Quest 的工具
So we built a tool called TwilioQuest,
帮助人们发掘他们的力量
to help people discover that power,
让他们知道 该怎么开始
to help them know where to get started,
不过我感觉 你知道 很多人一直在寻找自己的身份
but I just sense, you know, there's been this theme of people finding their identity,
或者 等着谁来批准他们获得身份
or getting permission to have that identity,
有很多写代码的人
and for every person that's writing code already,
或者说 用代码和软件解决问题的人
or solving problems with code or software,
但更多的人只是想要学会这项技能 却不知道如何开始
there's so many more who want to, and just don't know where to start yet.
我们对这件事非常上心
So that's a thing that's on our mind a lot.
确实
Yeah.
So Robyn, for you at Red Hat, what are Red Hat developers looking for?
Robyn 从你和红帽公司的角度 红帽的开发者都想要什么呢
情况经常是 有人找上你的时候
A lot of times, it's people who come to you
他们多半是遇到了什么障碍
and they've got some roadblock in their way,
有时候是 你知道
whether it's, you know,
“机器人没注意到我的 PR” 之类的
"Somehow my PR fell through the robot cracks,"
很多时候不是这样 他们遇到的困难可能是类似于
but a lot of times, it's also people who are like,
“嗨 我有个主意 我觉得很酷
"Hey, I had this cool idea.
它可能不太适合这里
Maybe it doesn't quite fit in here,
不过我觉得 它可能对社区运行有帮助
but I thought maybe it might improve how the community is running,
或者 说不定跟我们做的项目很配 我该怎么办？
or might be a good companion tool to other stuff that we're working on. What do I do?"
这时候 任务就变成了 “我该怎么帮你入门呢？”
And it's like, "Well, you know, how can I help you get started,"
你懂吧？“我该怎么帮你？你是需要被批准么？”
you know? "What can I do? Like, do you just need someone to say yes?"
我的全职工作就是开绿灯 基本上 你不管做什么都可以
Because I am here to say yes all day long, to basically anything,
让大家知道 你当然有权去做你想做的事”
and just let people know that yes, of course you have permission to do that,"
你懂的 我觉得 在我这个位置上能做到的 最棒的一件事
so that's, you know, I think the best thing that you can do, at least in my position,
就是保证大家前路畅通
is make sure people don't have things in their way,
如果他们需要被批准才能前进的话
or if the one thing that's in their way is waiting for someone to just say yes,
我一直重申 你不需要批准
I keep reiterating all the time that you don't need permission,
不过 如果有人需要批准 看在上帝的份上 那就准了他们吧
but if someone needs it, then by god, give it to them.
我们要结束了 这是最后一个问题
So, the last question, we need to wrap things up,
这个问题是问给你们每个人的
so I'm going to ask you each something.
在即将到来的 2019 年 你想要推广的 最重要的东西是什么
What is the single-most important thing that you're going to be advocating for in 2019?
如果你有魔杖 你想用魔法做出什么重大改变？
If you had a magic wand, what's the next big thing you'd want to change?
Sandra 从你开始吧
Sandra, let's start with you.
我就知道你会问这个
Oh, I knew you were going to do that.
我们2019年会面临的最大挑战
Well, the biggest challenges, and yet the most exciting projects
也是我们最激动人心的项目
that we're going to be working on for 2019,
是让我们的承诺真正兑现
is to truly deliver on our promise of
让互联网成为最好的 最大的 最易于使用的平台之一
the web being one of the greatest, biggest, most accessible platform.
我们总是鼓励开发者 为互联网开发 这样软件就能随地部署
We always tell developers it's where you should build, and deploy everywhere,
但我们知道 互联网本身非常复杂
but knowing that the web itself is incredibly complex,
有许多个浏览器供应商
and that we have multiple browser vendors out there,
我们说的话 有时候并不切合实际
sometimes that's not a true statement,
这是一项长期的挑战
and it's been a perennial challenge for us,
尤其对我们 Mozilla 而言
especially at Mozilla,
我们希望能让互联网开放、自由 让所有人都能使用
where we want to keep the web open, and free, and accessible for all.
我们希望能坚定不移地
We want to continue to make sure that
继续为开发者们兑现我们的承诺
we are fulfilling that promise to our developers,
让互联网的确开放、自由、人人可用
that the web is indeed open, accessible, and available to all.
爱了
Oh, love that.
Ricky 你呢
Ricky, what about you?
确保我们继续为开发者服务
Just making sure we're serving developers
不管他们在线上聚会 还是在线下集会 不管他们身处何方
where they gather, online and offline, throughout the entire world.
人很容易就会只记得他们能看到的东西
It can be super easy to get focused on what you see
然后忘记 其实开发者无处不在 就算你看不到他们
and forget that there's developers everywhere, even when you don't see them.
我要挥一挥魔杖 到世界各地去
So, I would wave my magic wand and just be more places all over the world,
找出能帮助那里的开发者的办法
finding out how we can help developers there.
我得说 我非常喜欢Jerod的一个说法：“暗物质开发者”
I just want to say, I loved Jarod's talk about dark matter developers.
这个概念非常的厉害
It was incredible.
你第一次听说的时候 会觉得 这个说法实在是绝妙
It's like such an amazing concept when you hear it for the first time.
你会觉得 “我去 还真是这么回事”
It's like, "Wow, that really is a thing."
说说看吧 什么是“暗物质开发者”呢
So tell us about that. What's a dark matter developer?
这就是说 有这么一些开发者
Essentially, there are developers out there,
他们不参加聚会
there are those who do not show up to your meetups,
他们不上 Github
who do not participate in GitHub,
不参与线上社区 不贡献Stack Overflow
online communities, do not contribute to Stack Overflow.
但他们是开发者 他们也在努力工作 做出贡献
Those are the developers who are still actively working and contributing,
但我们不知道
but we do not know.
我们知道他们存在 但我们看不见他们
We know that they're there, but we cannot see them.
我们不认识他们
We cannot identify them,
然而 他们在开发者的社区中 是很重要的一部分
and those are actually a very important segment of the developer community
也是经常遭到无视的一部分
that we tend to ignore,
我们不能继续无视了
and we cannot.
忽略那些不愿发表意见的社区 会损害我们与开发者的关系
It will be to our detriment working in developer relations,
to ignore the community that does not speak up,
我们需要更积极主动地
and we need to be more proactive
寻找宇宙中的暗物质开发者
in searching those dark matter developers out in our universe.
我喜欢 - 这个太酷了
Oh, I love ... Oh, that's very cool.
是啊 Jarod在Twilio工作 对吧？
Yeah, and Jarod actually works at Twilio, right?
是的 是的 他负责运营亚太区的 DevRel
Yes. Yes, he runs the APAC DevRel.
我从前在红帽的同事之一
One of my former Red Hat colleagues,
Chris Grams 现在在一家名为 Tidelift 的公司工作
who's now at a company called Tidelift, Chris Grams,
他写过一篇博客 标题是“暗物质很重要”
actually used to have a blog that was titled Dark Matter Matters,
注：此处标题是双关 亦可译为“暗物质也是物质”
这就像是
because it's sort of the -
你知道 你所看不到的东西其实仍然很重要 所以
You know, the things you don't see still actually matter, so -
Robin 你呢？
And Robyn, what about you.
你会用魔杖做什么呢？
What would you do with your magic wand?
有魔杖的话 能做好多事啊
Oh, with my magic wand, so many things,
但是 跟这次谈话最相关的是
but I guess pursuant to this conversation,
更好地管理各个社区之间的依赖关系
getting better at managing our dependencies upon each other,
不给人带来 “惊吓”
and maybe not surprising each other,
尤其是 我们中间还有那么多人
especially when so many of us
在OpenStack 在OPNFV 在Ansible工作
work in OpenStack, and OPNFV, and Ansible,
这些项目都是彼此依赖的
and all of these things that build on top of each other.
在不同的项目之间 建立更清晰的关系
Just making sure that the relationships between our projects is more obvious
而不是埋头工作 把这些统统无视
than things can be when you're head-down in stuff.
这是我期待明年能达成的事
So that's a thing I'm really looking forward to over the coming year,
我们现在有做事的动力 大家情绪都很高昂
because we're getting traction on stuff. It's very exciting right now.
有动力总是件好事
Traction is always just so good.
太叫人兴奋了
It's so exciting.
我想向大家道谢 非常 非常的感谢你们
Well, I want to thank all of you so, so much
来到这里 分享你们的所思所想 和你们的故事
for joining us today and sharing your minds, and your thoughts, and your stories.
非常感谢！各位来道别吧？
Thank you all so much. You want to say goodbye?
大家再见
Bye, y'all.
真不错 Saron 我很感谢
Nice. Thank you so much, Saron.
很高兴能参加这次座谈
It's been a pleasure being on this panel.
对 感谢你请我们来
Yes. Thanks, thanks for having us.
是啊
Absolutely.
今天的圆桌会议包括红帽的社区架构师 Robyn Bergeron
Today's roundtable included Robyn Bergeron, Community Architect at Red Hat,
Mozilla 的全球策略师 Sandra Persing
Sandra Persing, Global Strategist at Mozilla,
以及 Twilio 的开发者网络总监 Ricky Robinet
and Ricky Robinet, Director of the Developer Network at Twilio.
我认为自己很幸运
I consider myself hugely lucky
能有这样的平台让我分享 对于社区将何去何从的愿景
to have platforms where I get to share my vision for what our community could become,
无论是这档播客节目 还是在其他地方
whether here on this podcast or elsewhere,
但我想要指出 你无需拥有自己的播客就能够成为推广大使
but I want to point out, you do not have to have your own podcast to be an advocate.
成为推广大使只须睁大眼睛 并为他人发声
Being an advocate simply means you keep your eyes open
and you speak up on behalf of others.
每个人都能胜任这份工作
It really can be everybody's job.
我希望 Robyn、 Sandra 和 Ricky
So I'm hoping Robyn, Sandra, and Ricky
他们的谈话能对你有所启发 让你看到“推广”对你而言的意义
give you a little inspiration to advocate for matters to you.
同时 《代码英雄》第 3 季已经在制作中了
Meanwhile, Season 3of Command Line Heroes is already in the works.
节目会在春季推出 你可以抢先观看
You can be one of the first to learn about new episodes when they drop this spring.
如果你还没有订阅本节目
If you haven't already, subscribe over at Apple Podcasts, Google Podcasts,
请在 Apple Podcasts、Google Podcasts 或者其他地方订阅
or wherever you get your podcasts.
只需点击一下 百分百免费
It's one click, and it's 100% free.
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek.
在第 3 季到来之前 请继续编程
Thank you so much for listening, and until season 3, keep on coding.